杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们正生活在一个最令人兴奋的时代
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We're living in one
of the most exciting times as frontend
开发者。
developers.
因为在最初的时候，就像 Netscape 和
Because at the very beginning.,
like in the days of Netscape and
Internet Explorer.
你只需要打开一个文本文件，然后写一些 HTML 和
You were able to just open up
a text file and write some HTML and
你可以在网上放点东西。
you could put something on the Internet.
这真的，真的很容易接近。
And it was really, really approachable.
你有像 GeoCities 这样的东西，可以让你在网上得到一些东西。
You had things like GeoCities that allowed
you to just get something up on the web.
然后我们需要更多的能量，我们开始看到这种复杂性在蔓延。
And then we wanted more power and we
started to see this complexity creep in.
引入了一个全新的层次，只是你必须管理和处理的东西
JavaScript introduced a whole new level
of just stuff you had to manage and
一些很难做的事情。
things that got hard to do.
这就导致了工具的爆炸式增长，所以 jQuery 开始了。
And that resulted in this explosion of
tooling, so jQuery kind of kicks off.
当然，它本身并不是真正的 jQuery，但是
Well, not really jQuery on its own, but
很多类似 jQuery 的工具开启了这场革命。
a lot tools similar to jQuery
kicked off this revolution.
用我们管理 JavaScript 的方式。
In the way that we managed JavaScript.
然后这些就被捆绑机取代了咕噜和咕噜,
And then those kinda gave way
to bundlers Grunt and Gulp,
接下来是 Webpack 和 Parcel。
moving on to Webpack and Parcel.
巴贝尔打开了这个全新的工作流程
Babbel unlocked this
whole new workflow and
生态系统开始向外扩张。
the ecosystem started to expand outward.
现在我们开始看到的是，生态系统已经足够稳定
And now what we're starting to see is
that the ecosystem is stabilizing enough
它又开始收缩了。
that it's starting to contract again.
像盖茨比这样的作品还有 JAMstack 这样的作品,
And with something like Gatsby and
with stuff like the JAMstack,
你能做的就是打开一个浏览器。
what you're able to do is
basically open up a browser.
我把《了不起的盖茨比》改头换面，然后我就可以在橱窗里看到它。
And I run Gatsby new and
then I can just see it in the window.
我可以写一些代码，我可以在浏览器中看到它。
I can write some code and
I can see it in the browser.
我可以通过一个命令就可以看到我在网上构建的东西。
And I can get it up in one command and
see the thing that I built on the Web.
所以即使有了所有这些复杂性，我们已经开始达到了一个点。
So even with all of that complexity,
we've started to hit a point.
在那里我们可以轻松地在网上找到一些东西。
Where we get the ease of
getting something online.
只需要打开一个文本文件，编写一些代码，然后看着它上线。
Of just opening up a text file and
writing some code and seeing it go live.
但是我们得到了所有这些新工具的力量
But we get the power of all
of these new tools, and
几十年来在网络上所做的额外工作。
the decades of additional work
that's been done on the Web.
让它变得更加强大
To make it more powerful and
更有能力做这些真正不可思议的经历。
more capable of doing these
really incredible experiences.
除此之外，这个平台正在向端口扩展。
And beyond that the platform is
just expanding to port so much.
我们已经拿到了 JiroScope 和手机。
And we've got access the JiroScope and
the phone.
我们得到了相机，音频和光的灵敏度。
We got access to the camera and
audio and light sensitivity.
所有这些很酷的东西意味着我们可以建造,
And all these really cool things
that mean we can build really,
真正强大的东西在我们的浏览器。
really powerful stuff in our browsers.
我们不需要成为铁杆的、无所不知的开发者。
And we don't have to be hardcore,
know-everything developers.
我们真的可以专注于建立一个伟大的经验和
We can really just focus on
building a great experience and
不用担心 DevOps。
not worry about DevOps.
不用担心成为 WebPack 和 Babbel 的配置专家。
Not worry about being a configuration
expert for WebPack and Babbel.
我认为现在是成为前端开发者的好时机
And I think it's a good time
to be a frontend developer and
我认为它一直在变得更好。
I think that it's getting
better all the time.
所以我真的很高兴看到你们出去建造什么。
So I'm really excited to see
what y'all go out and build.
(掌声)
&gt;&gt; [APPLAUSE]